{"test_questions": [[{"question": "One litre of water occupies a volume of", "opta": "100 cm3", "optb": "250 cm3", "optc": "500 cm3", "optd": "1000 cm3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The value of bulk modulus of a fluid is required to determine", "opta": "Reynold's number", "optb": "Froude's number", "optc": "Mach number", "optd": "Euler's number", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a depressed nappe", "opta": "the pressure below the nappe is atmospheric", "optb": "the pressure below the nappe is negative", "optc": "the pressure above the nappe is atmospheric", "optd": "the pressure above the nappe is negative", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In one dimensional flow, the flow", "opta": "is steady and uniform", "optb": "takes place in straight line", "optc": "takes place in curve", "optd": "takes place in one direction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The kinematic viscosity is the", "opta": "ratio of absolute viscosity to the density of the liquid", "optb": "ratio of density of the liquid to the absolute viscosity", "optc": "product of absolute viscosity and density of the liquid", "optd": "product of absolute viscosity and mass of the liquid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diameter of the nozzle (d) for maximum transmission of power is given by (where D = Diameter of pipe, f = Darcy 's coefficient of friction for pipe, and l = Length of pipe )", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The discharge over a right angled notch is (where H = Height of liquid above the apex of notch)", "opta": "Cd 2g x H", "optb": "Cd 2g x H3/2", "optc": "Cd 2g x H2", "optd": "Cd 2g x H5/2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A weir is said to be broad crested weir, if the width of the crest of the weir is __________ half the height of water above the weir crest.", "opta": "equal to.", "optb": "less than", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A vertical wall is subjected to a pressure due to one kind of liquid, on one of its sides. The total pressure on the wall per unit length is (where w = Specific weight of liquid, and H = Height of liquid)", "opta": "wH", "optb": "wH/2", "optc": "wH2/2", "optd": "wH2/3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An error of 1% in measuring head over the apex of the notch (H) will produce an error of __________ in discharge over a triangular notch.", "opta": "1%", "optb": "1.5%", "optc": "2%", "optd": "2.5%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The length AB of a pipe ABC in which the liquid is flowing has diameter (d1) and is suddenly enlarged to diameter (d2) at B which is constant for the length BC. The loss of head due to sudden enlargement is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coefficient of contraction is the ratio of", "opta": "actual velocity of jet at vena contracta to the theoretical velocity", "optb": "loss of head in the orifice to the head of water available at the exit of the orifice", "optc": "actual discharge through an orifice to the theoretical discharge", "optd": "area of jet at vena contracta to the area of orifice", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a free nappe,", "opta": "the pressure below the nappe is atmospheric", "optb": "the pressure below the nappe is negative", "optc": "the pressure above the nappe is atmospheric", "optd": "the pressure above the nappe is negative", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Reynold's number of a ship is __________ to its velocity and length.", "opta": "directly proportional", "optb": "inversely proportional", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a tube of smaller diameter is dipped in water, the water rises in the tube due to viscosity of water.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to equation of continuity,", "opta": "w1a1 = w2a2", "optb": "w1v1 = w2v2", "optc": "a1v1 = a2v2", "optd": "a1/v1 = a2/v2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coefficient of resistance is the ratio of", "opta": "actual velocity of jet at vena contracta to the theoretical velocity", "optb": "area of jet at vena contracta to the area of orifice", "optc": "loss of head in the orifice to the head of water available at the exit of the orifice", "optd": "actual discharge through an orifice to the dieoretical discharge", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Euler's equation in the differential form for the motion of liquids is given by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "\u03c1.dp + g.dz + v.dv = 0", "optd": "\u03c1.dp - g.dz + v.dv = 0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to measure the flow with a venturimeter, it is installed in", "opta": "horizontal line", "optb": "inclined line with flow upwards", "optc": "inclined line with flow downwards", "optd": "any direction and in any location", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The discharge through a large rectangular orifice is given by (where H1 = Height of the liquid above the top of the orifice, H2 = Height of the liquid above the bottom of the orifice, b = Breadth of the orifice, and Cd = Coefficient of discharge)", "opta": "Q =  Cd x b2g(H2 - H1)", "optb": "Q =  Cd x b2g(H21/2 - H11/2)", "optc": "Q =  Cd x b2g(H23/2 - H13/2)", "optd": "Q =  Cd x b2g(H22 - H12)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The discharge over a rectangular notch is (where b = Width of notch, and H = Height of liquid, above the sill of the notch)", "opta": "Cd x b2gH", "optb": "Cd x b2g x H", "optc": "Cd x b2g x H3/2", "optd": "Cd x b2g x H2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The discharge through a siphon spillway is", "opta": "Cd x a2gH", "optb": "Cd x a2g x H3/2", "optc": "Cd x a2g x H2", "optd": "Cd x a2g x H5/2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum discharge over a broad crested weir is", "opta": "0.384 Cd x L x H1/2", "optb": "0.384 Cd x L x H3/2", "optc": "1.71 Cd x L x H1/2", "optd": "1.71 Cd x L x H3/2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a venturimeter, the velocity of liquid at throat is __________ than at inlet.", "opta": "higher", "optb": "lower", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The loss of head due to friction in a pipe of uniform diameter in which a viscous flow is taking place, is (where RN = Reynold number)", "opta": "1/RN", "optb": "4/RN", "optc": "16/RN", "optd": "64/RN", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of laminar flow?", "opta": "Under ground flow", "optb": "Flow past tiny bodies", "optc": "Flow of oil in measuring instruments", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pressure less than atmospheric pressure is known as", "opta": "suction pressure", "optb": "vacuum pressure", "optc": "negative gauge pressure", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total energy line lies over the hydraulic gradient line by an amount equal to the", "opta": "pressure head", "optb": "velocity head", "optc": "pressure head + velocity head", "optd": "pressure head - velocity head", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A structure whose width is __________ the width of the channel, is called a flumed structure.", "opta": "less than", "optb": "more than", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum efficiency of transmission through a pipe is", "opta": "50%", "optb": "56.7%", "optc": "66.67%", "optd": "76.66%", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The coefficient of viscosity may be determined by", "opta": "capillary tube method", "optb": "orifice type viscometer", "optc": "rotating cylinder method", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The stability of a dam is checked for", "opta": "tension at the base", "optb": "overturning of the wall or dam", "optc": "sliding of the wall or dam", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An ideal fluid is frictionless and incompressible.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A manometer is used to measure", "opta": "low pressure", "optb": "moderate pressure", "optc": "high pressure", "optd": "atomospheric pressure", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The centre of gravity of the volume of the liquid displaced is called", "opta": "centre of pressure", "optb": "centre of buoyancy", "optc": "metacentre", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The coefficient of discharge for an external mouthpiece is", "opta": "0.375", "optb": "0.5", "optc": "0.707", "optd": "0.855", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A tank of uniform cross-sectional area (A) containing liquid upto height (H1) has an orifice of cross-sectional area (a) at its bottom. The time required to empty the tank completely will be", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A siphon is used to connect two reservoirs at different levels intervened by a high ridge.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A flow in which the volume of a fluid and its density does not change during the flow is called __________ flow.", "opta": "incompressible", "optb": "compressible", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The loss of head due to an obstruction in a pipe is twice the loss of head at its entrance.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The body will sink down if the force of buoyancy is __________ the weight of the liquid displaced.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a body floating in a liquid returns back to its original position, when given a small angular displacement, the body is said to be in", "opta": "neutral equilibrium", "optb": "stable equilibrium", "optc": "unstable equilibrium", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The pressure measured with the help of a piezometer tube is in", "opta": "N/mm2", "optb": "N/m2", "optc": "head of liquid", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The power transmitted through a pipe is (where w = Specific weight in N/m3, and Q = Discharge in m3/s)", "opta": "w x Q x H", "optb": "w x Q x hf", "optc": "w x Q (H - hf)", "optd": "w x Q (H + hf)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an external mouthpiece, the absolute pressure head at vena contracta is __________ the atmospheric pressure head by an amount equal to 0.89 times the height of the liquid, above the vena contracta.", "opta": "less than", "optb": "more than", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The weight per unit volume of a liquid at a standard temperature and pressure is called", "opta": "specific weight", "optb": "mass density", "optc": "specific gravity", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The centre of buoyancy is the centre of area of the immersed body.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The metacentric heights of two floating bodies A and B are 1 m and 1.5 m respectively. Select the correct statement.", "opta": "The bodies A and B have equal stability", "optb": "The body A is more stable than body B", "optc": "The body B is more stable than body A", "optd": "The bodies A and B are unstable", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In open channels, the specific energy is the", "opta": "total energy per unit discharge", "optb": "total energy measured with respect to the datum passing through the bottom of the channel", "optc": "total energy measured above the horizontal datum", "optd": "kinetic energy plotted above the free surface of water", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Bernoulli's equation is based on the assumption that", "opta": "there is no loss of energy of the liquid flowing", "optb": "the velocity of flow is uniform across any cross-section of the pipe", "optc": "no force except gravity acts on the fluid", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}